Guide to the Roger W. Moss Collection of Manuscript, Original Art and Printed Material by and about Richard Shirley Smith
Yale Center for British Art, Rare Books and Manuscripts
- Publications Designed or Illustrated by Richard Shirley Smith, Series II
  - Songs by Finzi & His Friends. Long-play record for the 25th Anniversary Celebration of Gerald Finzi's death in 1956. London, Hyperion, Ltd., 1981., Finzi, Gerald, 1901-1956; 310 x 314 mm (Volume Moss no. 103)
    Drawn four-color sleeve (310 x 314 mm) illustrated and designed by Richard Shirley Smith.
  - Blewbury Festival Program of Events. June, 1981., Shirley Smith, Richard; Pp. [20]; 297 x 154 mm (Volume Moss no. 104)
    Richard Shirley Smith supplied the maps, many photographs, and designed this Blewbury, Oxfordshire, village festival brochure where he lived at the time. Stapled soft binding.
  - Buzz Buzz--Ten Insect Poems with a wood engraving by Richard Shirley Smith. The Gruffyground Press, Sidcot,1981., Heath-Stubbs, John, 1918-2006; Pp. [1-16]; 241 x 163 mm (Volume Moss no. 105)
    Designed, handset in Bodoni italic, and printed on Vélin d'Arches mould-made paper by Michael Mitchell at the Libanus Press, Marlborough, Wiltshire, for Anthony Baker of the Gruffyground Press, Ladram, Sidcot, Winscombe, Somerset. Shirley Smith pearwood engraving [Rhinoceros Beetle on title page; Bain no. 251] printed from the original block. The Libanus Press logo by Shirley Smith also appears on the colophon page [1975; Bain no. 235]. The edition is limited to two hundred copies; one hundred copies are signed by Shirley Smith and John Heath-Stubbs. The cover is ochre Mingei handmade paper wrapper printed in black. Sewn soft binding.
    According to Mark Askam, Gruffyground Press: A Bibliography, 1972-2007 (see item 36 above), John Heath-Stubbs wrote two slightly different versions of the poem 'Silverfish'. He could not decide which version to use, so it was decided that one half of the publication would be printed with one version of the poem and the other half with the other. In this copy, the end of line four in the first stanza of 'Silverfish' ends with 'Secondary Epoch'. Being completely blind, John Heath-Stubbs had to have his hand placed in the correct position on each colophon page in order to sign the copies. This accounts for the huge variation in his signatures and their most interesting, if rather illegible, nature.
  - Late in the Day. Hitchin, Herts: Mandeville Press, 2 Taylor's Hill, 1982., Riviere, Michael Valentine Briton, 1919-1997; Pp. [16]; 213 x 151 mm (Volume Moss no. 106)
    'An edition of 250 copies with a block from a wood-engraving ["The Candle"; Bain no. 133] by Richard Shirley Smith, of which 35 have been signed by the author' of which this is copy no. 18. Sewn soft cover.
  - Vines. Poems by David Burnett wood engravings by Richard Shirley Smith. The Rocket Press, Steventon, Abingdon, Oxfordshire, 1984., Burnett, David, 1937-; Pp. [1-24]; 216 x 155 mm (Volume Moss no. 107)
    First edition. Hand-set in Bell type and printed by Jonathan Stephenson at The Rocket Press on Zerkall mould-made paper. Bound with marbled paper from Compton Marbling and Richard de Bas hand-made endpapers. The edition is limited to 200 copies of which numbers 1 to 50 are hardbound with additional signed prints of the engravings, "Thais" and "Girl's Head" [Bain nos. 257 & 258] and numbers 51 to 200 are sewn into soft covers. This is number 32 of the 50 hardbound copies. Signed by Shirley Smith. The two engravings, signed and numbered xxxii/50, are each contained in individual folders with printed labels, all contained in a marbled-board slipcase. The poems are drawn from a larger collection entitled Thais. Six poems with images by Kenneth Lindley were published by the Pointing Finger Press of Hereford in a limited edition entitled Figures and Spaces in 1978 and a further fifty in Thais by the Black Cygnet Press of Durham in 1981.
  - Vines. Poems by David Burnett wood engravings by Richard Shirley Smith., 1984; Burnett, David, 1937-; Pp. [1-24]; 216 x 155 mm (Volume Moss no. 108)
    Poems by David Burnett wood engravings by Richard Shirley Smith. Copy no. 96 of the 150 in sewn soft binding as mentioned above. Signed by Shirley Smith.
  - The Cat: An Essay. Marlborough, Wiltshire: Libanus Press, 1984., Hartley, L. P. (Leslie Poles), 1895-1972; Pp. [1-12]; 157 x 97 mm (Volume Moss no. 109)
    Set in monotype Joanna. Cover illustrations by Richard Shirley Smith [cropped cat head and seated cat detail from the Benoît Junod engraved bookplate [1975, Bain no. 256; Lee no. 25]. One of 1200 unnumbered copies printed on Basingwerk Parchment, sewn into overlapping card covers.
  - Daylight Jobbery: Ephemera to 1985. First collection of ephemera from the commercial printings of Libanus Press. Marlborough, Wiltshire: Libanus Press, 1985., Libanus Press; 310 x 223 mm (Volume Moss no. 110)
    Twenty–six cards (310 x 223 mm), some with multiple samples affixed, plus index sheet. Includes eight items designed by or utilizing Richard Shirley Smith engravings. Seventy-five copies total. Clamshell box. Richard Shirley Smith's copy with his studio ex–libris.
    #1. RSS drawn boarder Calthorpe wedding invitation #3. RSS invitation to viewing 27 November 1982 [Head of Pan from Poems of Shelley, 'Hymn of Pan,' Bain no. 183] #12. RSS wood engraving Elliot, Recalling Spring [Libanus Press logo, Bain no. 235]#13. RSS letterhead [no illustration] #14. RSS wood engraving for exhibition at Katharine House Gallery 17 October 1982 [Flowery Wreath from Poems of Shelley, 'Elegy on the Death of Adonis,' Bain no. 180] #17. RSS wood engraving for exhibition at Katharine House Gallery 29 May 1983 ['Contessina Emilia Viviani' from Poems of Shelley, 'Epipsychidion,' Bain no. 186] #23. RSS wood engraving for exhibition at Katharine House Gallery Christmas 1982 ['Flowers and Scull in Basket' from Poems of Shelley, title page, Bain no. 81] #24. RSS wood engravings for The Sapient Pig Wine List and Menu ['Apples and Pear,' Bain no. 74]
  - Messer Pietro Mio. Letters between Lucrezia Borgia & Pietro Bembo. Marlborough, Wilshire: Libanus Press, 1985., Shankland, Hugh; Pp. [1-6] 7-46 [47-114]; 268 x 191 mm (Volume Moss no. 111)
    Printed in 14- point monotype Bembo on Barcham Green handmade Chester paper. Wood engravings by Richard Shirley Smith [Bain nos. 265-282]. Edition limited to 150 copies, numbered 1-135, and fifteen special copies with an extra set of prints identified as A-O. This is copy 54, signed by Shirley Smith. Bound in tan quarter morocco with embossed paper boards in slip case. Prospectus laid in.
  - Messer Pietro Mio. Marlborough, Wiltshire, Libanus Press, 28 July, 1985., Shankland, Hugh; 302 x 258 mm (Volume Moss no. 112)
    Boxed set of the seventeen wood engravings mounted in twelve window mats (302 x 258 mm); each signed by Richard Shirley Smith and numbered copy no. 23 of 100 copies and housed in a clamshell box covered in tan book cloth with pasted paper label 'Messer Pietro Mio The Engravings Richard Shirley Smith Libanus Press 1985' [Bain nos. 265-282]. Prospectus for the Messer Pietro Mio project together with a copy of Libanus Press, Book List for 1986 (4Pp.) laid in. The engravings for Messer Pietro Mio were cut between 1977 and 1985 and published in 1985. According to the prospectus the engravings reflect 'the metaphorical, heraldic and surreal elements contained in the letters.' They were the last major suite of wood engravings Shirley Smith produced before a detached retina at the age of fifty forced him to stop engraving and to concentrate on drawn images. According to Shirley Smith, only 30 of the projected 100 boxed sets of the engravings were actually assembled and distributed.
  - The Prettiest Love Letters in the World. Letters between Lucrezia Borgia & Pietro Bembo. London: Collins Harvill, 1987., Shankland, Hugh; Pp. [1-6] 7-46 [47-114]; 260 x 185 mm (Volume Moss no. 113)
    First English trade edition. Handset in 14- point Monotype Bembo. Bound in red book cloth with white dust jacket printed with Shirley Smith engravings.
  - The Prettiest Love Letters in the World. Letters between Lucrezia Borgia & Pietro Bembo. Boston: David R. Godine, 1987., Shankland, Hugh; Pp. [1-6] 7-46 [47-114]; 260 x 182 mm (Volume Moss no. 114)
    First United States trade edition. Printed and bound by Horowitz/Rae Book Manufacturers, Fairfield New Jersey, on Mohawk Ticonderoga Text. Bound in red book cloth with simple typeset dust jacket.
  - The Prettiest Love Letters in the World. Letters between Lucrezia Borgia & Pietro Bembo. Boston: David R. Godine, 1987., Shankland, Hugh; Pp. [1-6] 7-46 [47-114]; 254 x 177 mm (Volume Moss no. 115)
    Paperback of the Godine Press edition.
  - Nine Vignettes. Rocket Press, Blewbury, Oxfordshire, Merivale Editions, 1985., Shirley Smith, Richard; 293 x 212 mm (Volume Moss no. 116)
    Nine engravings on royal 8vo/A4 sheet of Zerkall mould-made paper (293 x 212 mm), contained in a green card folder with printed descriptive text. Edition limited to 500 numbered copies of which this is no. 408 signed by Shirley Smith; the engravings were printed by Jonathan Stephenson directly from the original boxwood blocks used for The Gourmet's Garden (1964) [Bain nos. 44–53]. See entry no. 52.
  - Cat Therapy. Hebden Bridge, West Yorkshire: Littlewood Press, [1986]., Schneider, Myra, 1936-; Pp. [1-6] 7-47 [48]; 209 x 148 mm (Volume Moss no. 117)
    Printed by Tony Ward at the Arc & Throstle Press, The Old Fire Station, Todmorden, Lancs. Typeset by Bryan Williamson, Swinton, Berwickshire. Richard Shirley Smith's engraving 'Portrait of Pépé' [1980; Bain no. 245] on front cover and 'Artist's Cats' [1981; Bain no. 252] on the back cover. Perfect bound soft cover.
  - The Testament of Charlotte B. Marlborough, Wiltshire: Libanus Press, 1988., Kociejowski, Marius; Pp. [1-2] [i-vi] vii-xv [xvi-xviii] 19-68 [69-72]; 264 x 165 mm (Volume Moss no. 118)
    Set in monotype Garamond printed on handmade Amatruda paper and bound by Smith Settle of Otley. Richard Shirley Smith decorations [line drawings including cover and five chapter heads, one repeated]. Edition of 220 copies, 50 of which have been specially bound, signed by the editor, and numbered in Roman numerals of which this is copy XXX/50. Quarter blue leather binding with decorative printed boards; blue binding cloth clamshell box. Libanus Press prospectus laid in.
  - Surplus Pages from a Cross Section in 1988. Fleece Press, 1988., Society of Wood Engravers; Pp. [44]; 288 x 210 mm (Volume Moss no. 119)
    First edition. Printed by Simon Lawrence, Seckar House, Seckar Lane, Woolley, Wakefield, West Yorkshire. One of 95 copies bound in Laura Ashley cloth, 8 wood engravings and preliminary pages with a sample of a patterned paper designed by Edwina Ellis used for 218 copies thus bound. Wood engravings by Ray Hedger, Yvonne Skargon, Richard Shirley Smith [bookplate for Anne Stevens; Bain no. 255], Howard Phipps, Monica Poole, Geoffrey Wales, Kathleen Lindsley, Edwina Ellis. Bound in pink check Laura Ashley cloth.
  - On Gardens. His Essay, taken from the first complete collection which was published in 1625, the year before his death. Libanus Press, 1989., Bacon, Francis, 1561-1626; 270 x 183 mm (Volume Moss no. 120)
    'This essay was printed for the Libanus Press Open Day, 29 April 1989. This is limited to about 450 copies. The title page decoration is by Richard Shirley Smith.' Two unnumbered pages (270 x 183 mm), sewn into a wrapper. This item was included as a 'surprise packet' in the Libanus Press, More Daylight Jobbery.
  - A Keepsake of the talk given by Peter Sampson of Merivale Editions to the Oxford Guild of Printers on Saturday 30 September 1989., Shirley Smith, Richard; 179 x 177 mm (Volume Moss no. 121)
    The Rocket Press. Folded card stock (179 x 177 mm) with interior window mat holding two Shirley Smith wood engravings [Bain nos. 46, 50 originally used for The Gourmet's Garden, 1964]. Signed and dated by Shirley Smith.
  - More Daylight Jobbery, 1986-1990. Second collection of ephemera from the commercial printings of Libanus Press, Marlborough, Wiltshire, 1990., Libanus Press; 339 x 239 mm (Volume Moss no. 122)
    Twenty-nine cards (339 x 239 mm), several containing multiple samples affixed, plus index sheet. Illustrations by John Lawrence, Ian Beck, Richard Shirley Smith, Peter Forster, and Myra Dean. Includes Francis Bacon, On Gardens. Libanus Press, 1989, with 'decorations by Richard Shirley Smith'. Clamshell box.
  - Dramatic Monologues. Selected and introduced by A. S. Byatt, illustrated by Richard Shirley Smith. London: The Folio Society, 1991., Browning, Robert, 1812-1889; Pp. [i-v] vii-xxxi [xxxii] 1-310 [311-312]; 228 x 160 mm (Volume Moss no. 123)
    Typeset in 10-point monotype Bodoni with Modern 20 for display by Gloucester Typesetting, printed in red-brown and black by Butler and Tanner. Shirley Smith's illustrations consist of a drawn frontispiece and thirty-two drawn cartouches and vignettes (15 used twice, one used thrice, and one used four times)–all printed in red-brown. Bound by Butler and Tanner in quarter dark red cloth, white paper boards over-printed with a pattern in pink and brown by Shirley Smith. Pale brown slip case. [There was a second printing in 1992.]
  - Prospectus 1991. London: The Folio Society, 1991., Folio Society (London, England); Pp. [1] 2-92; 210 x 148 mm (Volume Moss no. 124)
    Set in Ehrhardt type and printed on Opal matt-coated Art paper. The cover is printed on Parchmarque board, with a design and hand-drawn lettering by John Andrew. Soft bound glued cover. Announcement of Robert Browning, Dramatic Monologues with sample page on pages 22-23.
  - The Spectator. Vol. 267, no 8528 (December 21/28, 1991). (Volume Moss no. 125)
    Cover design by Richard Shirley Smith. Colorful acrylic painting of holiday revelers in reindeer suit mounted by a hound in Santa suit flying a banner reading "Comes But Once A Year" and "Deo Gratias".
  - Perfect and Imperfect Enjoyments: poems by John Wilmot, Earl of Rochester. Introduction by Christopher Hibbert and illustrated with paintings by Richard Shirley Smith. London: The Folio Press, 1992., Rochester, John Wilmot, Earl of, 1647-1680; Pp. [1-6] 7-109 [110-112]; 310 x 214 mm (Volume Moss no. 126)
    Eight leaves of two-color lithographed plates [facingPp. 3, 19, 30, 52, 70, 89, 95 and 96]. Typeset in monotype Garamond. Printed on white Magnani mould-made paper by Stamperia Valdonega, Verona, Italy, photolithographic plates printed at the Senecio Press, Charlbury, Oxfordshire. Five hundred numbered copies printed of which 450 copies are quarter bound in Oasis morocco and 50 special copies are bound in full vellum with a separate portfolio of illustrations. In addition to the 500 numbered copies, 40 additional lettered copies (35 standards and five specials) were printed and bound for private distribution by the Society. This copy is signed and numbered 168/500. Bound by the Fine Bindery in quarter dark red morocco, Cockerell marbled paper boards; dark green endleaves. Dark green clamshell box, printed paper cover-label and leather spine-label. Folio Society color prospectus laid in.
  - The Boke of Iford. Introduction by Robert Whalley. Marlborough, Wiltshire: Libanus Press, 1993., Peto, Harold A. (Harold Ainsworth), 1854-1933; Pp. [1-2], [1-4], 5-53 [54]; 295 x 200 mm (Volume Moss no. 127)
    Twelve drawings by Richard Shirley Smith, six of which are cappriccios encompassing the sculptural and architectural elements of the garden. Edition limited to 200 copies; twenty-five copies printed on Vélin Arches rag paper and hand-colored at the press by Shirley Smith, bound in quarter leather in slipcase; 175 copies printed on Zerkall mould-made paper, bound at Smith Settle of Otley in paper-covered boards with linen spine and printed endpapers also designed by Shirley Smith of which this is an unnumbered proof copy, so marked with the Libanus Press blind stamp. Prospectus laid in.
  - The Boke of Iford Introduction by Robert Whalley. Marlborough, Wiltshire: Libanus Press, 1993., Peto, Harold A. (Harold Ainsworth), 1854-1933; Pp. [i-ii] [1-4] 5-53 [54]; 290 x 200 mm (Volume Moss no. 128)
    Set in monotype Bembo. Cover design by Richard Shirley Smith, title page boarder and eleven drawn illustrations. Perfect bound soft cover edition. Prospectus and sample page laid in.
  - My First Alphabet. Published by John Loch, The Market House, Aldbourne, 1994., Loch, John Hugh, 1923-; Pp. [i-x] 1-180 [181-182]; 250 x 175 mm (Volume Moss no. 129)
    Designed by Libanus Press, Marlborough; photoset in monotype Spectrum. Printed and bound by Smith Settle, Otley. First edition. One of 115 unnumbered copies. Frontispiece drawn portrait by Richard Shirley Smith, also 'Aldbourne Bookplate' by Shirley Smith reproduced opposite contents page [Bain no. 254 and North Lee no. 23]. Perfect bound soft cover.
  - Metamorphoses. Translated and introduced by Mary M. Innes illustrations by Richard Shirley Smith. London: The Folio Society, 1995., Ovid, 43 B.C.-17 A.D. or 18 A.D.; Pp. [i-iv] v-xxix [xxx-xxxii] 1-350 [351-352]; 252 x 178 mm (Volume Moss no. 130)
    Eight leaves of color reproductions of paintings by Shirley Smith (facingPp. 32, 49, 97, 112, 225, 240, 288 and 305). In addition to the plates there are thirteen tail-pieces (one used twice) and the title-page design, which incorporates the main title and imprint in a pastiche of a classical monumental inscription. Typeset in 13- point Baskerville with Fry's Baskerville for display. Typeset by Gloucester Typesetting Services, printed and bound by The Bath Press on Hamilton Wove and Mohawk Superfine paper and bound by them in quarter leatherette with pale grey cloth sides over-printed in dark green with a drawing by Shirley Smith, after Bernini. Gray slip case. Color prospectus (4Pp.) from The Folio Society for the Ovid laid in.
  - Ten Letters to Two Young Artists Working in Italy: Juliet Wood & Richard Shirley Smith. Preface by John Montague, introduction by Shirley Smith, edited by Derek Shiel. London: Agenda Editions, 1996., Jones, David, 1895-1974; Pp. [1-8] 9-51 [52–54]; 282 x 215 mm (Volume Moss no. 131)
    Designed by Shirley Smith; typeset by Libanus Press, Marlborough; printed and bound by Smith Settle, Otley, West Yorkshire. First edition. Edition limited to 160 copies of which this is no. 105. Shirley Smith signed wood-engraving in chemise envelope (the dedicatory engraving "J. to G.F." from A Point of Departure by Joyce Finzi; Bain no. 11). Quarter bound in tan book cloth, boards illustrated with squeeze of a Roman inscription made by Shirley Smith in Rome. Slipcase.
  - The Folio Golden Treasury--The Best Songs and Lyrical Poems in the English Language. London: The Folio Society, 1997., Brett, Simon, 1943-; Pp. [i-iv] v-xxxiv [1-6] 733 [734-736]; 280 x 190 mm (Volume Moss no. 132)
    Typeset in Baskerville at The Folio Society and printed at St Edmundsbury Press on Balmoral Book Wove paper bound by Hunter & Foulis, Edinburgh. 'Illustrated with wood engravings by various artists selected by Simon Brett.' Included are engravings by Shirley Smith illustrating sections: 8, 169, 170, 171, 187, 205, 224 (three engravings), 291, 292, 294, 296, 298, 299, 300 (two engravings), 301 (two engravings), 302 (three engravings)––in all 22 engravings, many of which had previously been commissioned for Folio Society books. Bound in quarter leather with cloth sides over-printed with a design by Simon Brett contained in a slip case.
  - Complete Plays. Edited by Stanley Wells and Gary Taylor; Introduced by Jonathan Bate. London: The Folio Society, 1997., Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616; 240 x 159 mm (Volume Moss no. 133)
    Set in Baskerville by Oxford University Press, with play titles hand set in Fournier by Speedspools, Edinburgh. Printed at the Bath Press, Bath, on Caxton wove paper and bound by them in Oxford Library Buckram with paper sides printed with designs by Richard Shirley Smith. Eight volumes in two slip cases also decorated by Shirley Smith.
  - Forbidden Fruit: Selected Tales in Verse. Translated by Guido Waldman Illustrated by Richard Shirley Smith. London: Harvill Press, 1998., La Fontaine, Jean de, 1621-1695; Pp. [i-viii] 1-85 [86]; 205 x 138 mm (Volume Moss no. 134)
    Designed and set in Fournier at Libanus Press, Marlborough, Wiltshire. Printed by Butler and Tanner, Ltd., Selwood Printing, Burgess Hill. Shirley Smith line drawn illustrations [nine full page, two of which are reused for dust jacket, chapter rule, and seven smaller drawings, some of which are used more than once]. Bound in blue book cloth with dust jacket.
  - Forbidden Fruit: Selected Tales in Verse. Translated by Guido Waldman Illustrated by Richard Shirley Smith. London: Harvill Press, 1998., La Fontaine, Jean de, 1621-1695 (Volume Moss no. 135)
    Perfect bound paperback copy of the above.
  - Memoirs Laughing and Dancing Our Way to the Precipice. Translated by Felice Harcourt. London: Harvill Press, 1999., La Tour du Pin Gouvernet, Henriette Lucie Dillon, marquise de, 1770-1853; Pp. [1-13] 14-468 [469-472]; 221 x 150 mm (Volume Moss no. 136)
    'Cover illustration of Madame de La Tour du Pin by Richard Shirley Smith series design by Libanus Press'. Harvill Press logo by Shirley Smith [Bain no. 264] on title page. Perfect bound soft cover.
  - Cat Cuts: A Collection of Engravers' Cats. London: Primrose Hill Press, 1999., Macgregor, Miriam; Pp. [1-6] 7- 46 [47-48]; 252 x 67 mm (Volume Moss no. 137)
    Designed and typeset by Oblong, Otley; printed and bound by Smith Settle, Otley. First edition. Includes three Richard Shirley Smith wood engravings: Benoît Junod bookplate [1983, Bain no. 256, North Lee no. 25], 'Portrait of Pépé' [1980; Bain no. 245], and 'The Artists' Cats', 1981 [Bain no. 252]. Bound in dark blue book cloth with dust jacket.
  - The Eclogues. Translated by James Michie. Introduction by Gilbert Highet. Decorations by Richard Shirley Smith. London: The Folio Society, 2000., Virgil; Pp. [i-v] vi-xvi [xvii-xviii] [ 1] 2-61 [62]; 250 x 178 mm (Volume Moss no. 138)
    Typeset in Centaur at the Folio Society; printed by Butler and Tanner, Frome, on Rivoli rag-content paper and bound by them. Frontispiece and 21 other line drawings used for chapter heads, etc. Bound in book cloth with paper sides over-printed with a design by Shirley Smith, contained in a slipcase.
  - Building Towers, Forming Gardens: Landscaping by Hamilton, Hoare and Beckford. London: St. Barnabas Press, 2002., Thacker, Christopher; Pp. [1-6] 7-126 [127-128]; 264 x 195 mm (Volume Moss no. 139)
    First edition. Designed by Humphrey Stone and printed by BAS Printers, Ltd., Over Wallop, Stockbridge, Hampshire. Limited edition of 150 copies of which this is no. 71 signed on the half title page by Richard Shirley Smith. A set of the four engravings [1989; Bain nos. 285-288] signed and numbered 71/150 contained in a chemise. Color reproductions of four commissioned illustrations by Shirley Smith tipped in. Endpapers reproduce the 1823 map of the Fonthill estate. Bound in patterned yellow book cloth designed by Shirley Smith.
    Ian Bain lists this book as Enchanting Paths to Paradise, c. 1989. The title was changed prior to publication in 2002. The four engravings for this project were the last wood engravings executed by Shirley Smith.
  - Building Towers, Forming Gardens: Landscaping by Hamilton, Hoare and Beckford. London: St. Barnabas Press, 2002., Thacker, Christopher; Pp. [1-6] 7-126 [127-128]; 258 x 188 mm (Volume Moss no. 140)
    Without the color reproductions tipped into the limited edition, one of which is reproduced on the cover in color. Signed by Richard Shirley Smith on the half title page. Perfect bound soft binding.